American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIh. 1892-1896 APS.Archives.IIh APS.Archives.IIh
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 2, 1894; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Concerns memorial volume of sesquicentennial addresses.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 2, 1894; 10-1/2x8; Spencer, J. W. (Joseph William), 1851-1921
    Atlanta, Ga., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Gabb's Topography of San Domingo.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 3, 1894; 8x5; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his Menonomie vocabulary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 4, 1894; 3-3/4x6-1/4; West Virginia historical and antiquarian society, Charleston
    Charleston, W. Va., Printed L. on postal card, filled in in Ms. 1p. and add. Invitation to fourth Annual Meeting.
  - Announcement of meeting sent to Robert E[llis] Thompson, Jan. 5, 1894; 3x5-1/4; American Philosophical Society
    [Phila.,]. Printed D. on postal card 1p., end. with note of Thompson's resignation, and add., end.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 6, 1894; 9x5-3/4; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his "Catalogue of Works on Atmospheric Physics and Climatology." For printed catalogue, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp. 248-269.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 6, 1894; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Rogers, Robert William, 1864-1930
    Madison, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Change of address.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 8, 1894; 11x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Sends books for library.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 8, 1894; 8x5; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his Menonomie grammar and vocabulary.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 8, 1894; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns gift of books and maps for the library.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 8, 1894; 9x5-3/4; Seiler, Carl
    Phila., L. 1p. Asks for copies of Mrs. Lesley's memorial to Emma Seiler. For memorial, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 29, pp. 151-158. Written on verso is copy of Phillips' reply. See Phillips to Seiler, Jan. 9, 1894.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 8, 1894; 10-1/4x8; Woolman, Lewis
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Enc. wanting. Forwards J.W. Spencer's letter asking for copy of Gabb's Topography of San Domingo. For enclosure, see Spencer to A.P.S., Jan. 2, 1894.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 9, 1894; 8x5; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will write obituary of G. de B. Keim.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Jan. 9, 1894; 8x5; Faxon, Edwin
    Jamaica Plain, Mass., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Asks about Nuttall's North American Sylva.
  - Letter to W. H. Phillips [sic], Jan. 9, 1894; 8x5; Mitchell, Silas Weir
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Recommends A.P.S. publication of Dr. Wright's paper on bacteria in the Phila. water supply.
  - Letter to [Carl] Seiler, Jan. 9, 1894; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Copy. Knows nothing of printed copies of Mrs. Lesley's memorial of Emma Seiler. For memorial, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 29, pp. 151-158. Written on verso of C. Seiler to phillips, Jan. 8, 18, 94.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 9, 1894; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, [Pa.] A.L.S. 1p. Will read paper on present and future of Pennsylvania forests at next meeting. For paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 33, p. 153.
  - Receipt for registered mail sent to H[ilborne] T[homson] Cresson, Jan. 9, 1894; 3x5-1/4; United States. Post Office, Philadelphia
    Phila., Printed D. filled in in MS., on postal card 1p. and add.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips:, Jan. 10, 1894; 3x4-3/4; Cresson, Hilborne Thomson
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Thanks for requested package.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 11, 1894; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Vincent, Mitchell
    Onawa, Iowa, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of Coues' description of the Lewis and Clark journals, and other material.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 12, 1894; 9x5-3/4; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns printing of his "Catalogue of works on Atmospheric Physics and Climatology." For printed work, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp. 248-269.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Jan. 12, 1894; 7x4-1/2; Hyatt, Alpheus, 1838-1902
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 2p., end. Asks for certain books.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 12, 1894; 8x5; Mitchell, Silas Weir
    L.S. by secretary. 1p., end. Arranges a meeting.
  - Letter to [Ella M. Morison], Jan. 12, 1894; 3-3/4x10-1/4; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerns gift of maps he has sent for library.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 13, 1894; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Sends the copy.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 16, 1894; 9-1/4x8-1/2; McKenna, Thomas P.
    Long Branch, N.H., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for particulars on Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 16, 1894; 3x5, 3-1/4x5-1/2; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. and add. end. Concerns memorial volume of sesquicentennial addresses. Refers to Blodget's Catalogue of Works on Atmospheric Physics and Climatology. For printed catalogue, see: APS Proceedings, vol 32, pp. 248-269.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 19, 1894; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Stokes, Alfred C.
    Trenton, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks address of J.E. Humphrey.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 20, 1894; 8x5; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 2p .Concerns his paper on tertiary Tipulidae. Refers to Harriet Biddle. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 163-245.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 22, 1894; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Iowa State University
    Iowa City, Typed L.S.: Emlin McClain 1p. Asks for particulars about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 23, 1894; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    Phila., Typed L.S., with MS. corrections. 1p., end. Withdraws nomination of Edm. Landolt of Paris, on advice of an APS Councillor.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Jan. 23, 1894; 6x4; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns plates for his paper on tertiary Tipulidae. For printed paper. see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 163-245.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 23, 1894; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Société royale de géographie d'Anvers
    Antwerp, Printed L. filled in in MS. on postal card 1p., end., and add. In French. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Jan. 24, 1894; 7x4-1/2; Nadaillac, Jean-François-Albert du Pouget, marquis de, 1818-1904
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. Will send photograph. Hopes to see him in France soon.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 24, 1894; 9-3/4x8; Sons of the Revolution. Pennsylvania Society
    Phila., Typed L.S.: E. A. Weaver, Secretary. 1p., end. Asks for copy of A.P.S. constitution and by-laws, and a list of members.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 25, 1894; 10-1/2x8; Craven, E. R. (Elijah Richardson), 1824-1908
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks question about Elias Boudinot. Referred to APS by J.Y. Burk.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 27, 1894; 9x6; Appleton, William Hyde, 1838?-1926
    Swarthmore, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Corrects his address in list of members.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 27, 1894; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Philadelphia College of Pharmacy
    Phila., A.L.S.: Tho[ma]s S. Wiegand, librarian. 1p., end. Needs No. 138 of the Proceedings to complete his file.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 27, 1894; 8-1/4x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends receipt for Proceedings. Concerns nomination of H.A. duPont.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Jan. 29, 1894; 6-1/4x4; McGee, S. C.
    Omaha, Neb., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for particulars on Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 30, 1894; 10-1/2x8; Craven, E. R. (Elijah Richardson), 1824-1908
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his question about Elias Boudinot.
  - Letter to H[enry] M. Phillips [sic], Jan. 30, 1894; 8x5-1/2; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will send his photograph.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Jan. 30, 1894; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Dr. Wright's paper on the water supply of Philadelphia. Refers to G.F. Barker, S.W. Mitchell, J.S. Billings. On verso is Fraley's reply. See Fraley to Phillips, [Jan. 1894]
  - Letter to [Henry] Philipps [sic], Jan. 31, 1894; 9x6; Hilprecht, H. V. (Hermann Vollrat), 1859-1925
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Will prepare obituary of Seidensticker Asks about appropriation for next volume of cuneiform inscriptions.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Jan. 31, 1894; 9x5-3/4; Lea Brothers & Company
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 31, 1894; 7x4-1/2; Ryder, John A. (John Adam), 1852-1895
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Will meet Bache and Barker to discuss Wright's paper on bacteria in water supply of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 31, 1894; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.s.: F. W. Hodge, Librarian 1p. Inquires about delayed shipment of publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 31, 1894; 8x5-1/4; University of Pennsylvania. Library
    Phila., A.L.S.: Gregory B[ernard] Keen. 1p. Asks for any available works by Phillips. Refers to Transactions, Hilprecht.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips;], Jan., 1894; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Phila., L. 1p. Appoints Ryder, Barker and Bache as committee, and Hilprecht to prepare obituary of Seidensticker. Written on verso of letter from Phillips to Fraley, Jan. 30, 1894.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society; Phila.], Feb. 1, 1894; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 2p. Sends estimate for plates for paper on the fishes of the Rio Grande do Sul. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 33, pp. 84-108.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 1, 1894; 8x5; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns plates for his paper on tertiary Tipulidae. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 163-245.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 1, 1894; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Steiner, Bernard Christian, 1867-1926
    Baltimore, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Announces death of John Leyburn.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 6, 1894; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Aley, Robert J. (Robert Judson), 1863-1935
    Bloomington, Ind. A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about papers by Daniel Kirkwood.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 7, 1894; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 2p., end. Asks to borrow plated used for his paper on gases. Refers to Remsen. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 149-236. On verso is copy of Phillips' reply. See H. Phillips to F.C. Phillips, Feb. 10, 1894.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 8, 1894; 11x8-3/4; Buenos Aires (Argentina: Province). Dirección General de Estadística
    LA Plata, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Carlos P. Salas 1p. In French. Announces his appointment as director general.
  - Letter to [Henry] P[hillips], Feb. 9, 1894; 7x4-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Approves loan of plates to F.C. Phillips.
  - Letter to [Francis Clifford Phillips], Feb. 10, 1894; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    L. 1p. Copy. Specifies terms of loan of plates used for his paper on gases, in APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 149-236. Written on verso of F.C. Phillips to H. Phillips, Feb. 7, 1894.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 12, 1894; 10-1/2x8; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns borrowing of plates. Refers to Ira Remsen, Alfred J. Phillips.
  - Letter to [Daniel Garrison] Brinton, Feb. 12, 1894; 8x5; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends list of issues of Proceedings which he needs.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 13, 1894; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Stokes, Alfred C.
    Trenton, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks for copy of Humphrey's paper on Saprolegniaceae. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 63-148.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 14, 1894; 7x4-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Concerns G.W. Childs. Refers to Ruschenberger.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 14, 1894; 9x5-3/4; University of Pennsylvania. Library
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Gregory B[ernard] Keen 1p. Thanks for gift of books and pamphlets.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 14, 1894; 11x8-1/2; Virginia Historical Society
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S.: Philip A[lexander] Bruce. 1p. Concerns status of historical society publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Philips [sic], Feb. 16, 1894; 11x8-1/2; Butler, James Davie, 1815-1905
    Madison, [Wis.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Friendly letter. Questions on Lewis and Clark journals.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 17, 1894; 3-1/2x6-1/4; Geyer, Henry F. (Henry Francis), 1839-1932
    Phila., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks for copy of last annual report and by-laws.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 17, 1894; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, [N.J.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p., and add. Concerns plates.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 18, 1894; 9-1/2x6; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Tallapoosa, Ga., A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter with news about his family and trip. Advises as to Brown and the rents.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 21, 1894; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns spelling of name of new member, Herman Snellen.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 23, 1894; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns spelling of name of new member, Herman Snellen.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 26, 1894; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Refers to obituary for G.W. Childs, the Magellanic premium, J.S. Price, Judge Dillon's legal paper, the Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 28, 1894; 6x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Will read paper on "Association: The Dominating Need of Man and the Keynote of Social Science" at next meeting. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 33, pp. 134-140.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 1, 1894; 8x5; Sagebeer, Joseph
    Flemington, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for particulars on Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], March 2, 1894; 8x5; Harding, Samuel Bannister, 1866-1927
    Boston], Typed L.S. 1p. Asks about R.H. Lee papers. On verso of letter is Phillips' reply, undated.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 2, 1894; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Pennsylvania. Governor (1891-1895: Pattison)
    Harrisburg, Pa., Typed L. 1p. Concerns public documents.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 2, 1894; 8x5; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, [Mass.] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Meisel's work on plates for his paper on tertiary Tipulidae. For Printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 163-245.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 3, 1894; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hyatt, Alpheus, 1838-1902
    Cambridge, Mass., Typed L.S. 2p., end. Concerns his paper on "Phylogeny of an acquired characteristic." Refers to S.H. Scudder. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 349-647.
  - Letter to [Alpheus] Hyatt, March 5, 1894; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L. 1p. Copy. Concerns Hyatt's paper on "Phylogeny of an acquired characteristic." Refers to S.H. Scudder. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 349-647.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 5, 1894; 10-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns plates being made by Werner & Winter. At bottom of page is Phillips' reply. See Phillips to Scott, March 7, 1894.
  - Letter to Henry M. Phillips [sic], March 5, 1894; 5-1/4x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for last announcement of Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 6, 1894; 8x5; Harding, Samuel Bannister, 1866-1927
    [Boston], Typed L.S. with MS. corrections. 2p.,end. Concerns making copy of R.H. Lee papers. Refers to copy made for Justin Winsor.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 6, 1894; 8-1/4x5; Hyatt, Alpheus, 1838-1902
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on "Phylogeny of an acquired characteristic." Refers to S.H. Scudder. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 349-647.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 7, 1894; 3-1/2x5-1/2; H[orn], G[eorge] H[enry], 1840-1897.
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end. and add. Business mater.
  - Letter to [William Berryman Scott], March 7, 1894; 10-1/2x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Draft. Concerns plates being made by Werner & Winter. Written at bottom of letter from Scott to Phillips, March 5, 1894.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 9, 1894; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, [Mass.] A.L.S. on postal card 1p., and add. Printing of plates ordered.
  - Letter to Charles Truscott, March 10, 1894; 9x5-1/2; Bush-Brown, Henry Kirke, 1857-1935
    Newburgh, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p., end., and end. Gives permission to photograph sketch of the Rittenhouse [portrait?] Refers to H. Phillips.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 12, 1894; 11-1/2x9; Hiersemann, Karl W.
    Leipzig, Typed L.S.1p. Offers a German encyclopedia for sale.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 13, 1894; 8x5; Ruschenberger, W. S. W. (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for copy of letter from Judge Hopkinson, presenting portrait of Corrêa da Serra from the Academy.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 14, 1894; 6x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Has not received notice of next meeting.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 14, 1894; 8x5; Sons of the Revolution. Pennsylvania Society
    [Phila.], A.L.S.: E. A. Weaver, Secy. 2p. Inquires about John Rhea, member of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 16, 1894; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Cannot attend meeting. Sends apologies to H.C. Baird.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 17, 1894; 6x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for his paper in order to copy it.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 19, 1894; 11x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends subscription form for painting of George Ord's portrait by T. Henry Smith.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 19, 1894; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Subscribes to portrait of George Ord.
  - Letter to [William Houston] Greene, March 22, 1894; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Marshall, John, 1855-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends check for subscription to collations. Asks him to go duck hunting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 22, 1894; 13x8-1/4
    [London], Printed L. filled in in MS. 3p. Concerns continuation of its Catalogue of scientific papers.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 26, 1894; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, [Mass.] A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns plates by Meisel for his paper on tertiary Tipulidae. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 163-245.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 27, 1894; 6x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns portrait of George Ord. Mentions Academy of natural sciences, John Penington.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 27, 1894; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Certificates of membership have been signed. Refers to Ruschenberger, L.A. Scott.
  - Letter to Samuel H[ubbard] Scudder, March 29, 1894; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Meisel, Berthold
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Plates for Scudder's paper on tertiary Tipulidae have been sent to MacCalla & co. Encloses bill and diagrams.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 30, 1894; 7x4-1/2; Morison, Ella M.
    Atlantic City, [N.J.], A.L.S. 2p. Cannot work until Monday. Refers to H.C. Baird.
  - Letter to [Samuel Bannister Harding, March, 1894; 8x5; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L. 1p. Copy. Answers his question about R.H. Lee papers. Refers to Justin Winsor. Written on verso of Harding to Phillips, March 2, 1894.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 3, 1894; 10x7-3/4; Cresson, Hilborne Thomson
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Zapotec calendar as given by Cordoba.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 3, 1894; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends requested check. Inquires about size of Meisel's bill.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 4, 1894; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Will make communication on anatomy of Ophidia at next meeting. For communication, see: APS Proceedings vol. 33, pp. 217-224.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 9, 1894; 3-1/2x5-1/2; American Institute of Electrical Engineers
    Phila., A.L.S.: Elmer G. Willyoung, on postal card 1p., end., and add. Invitation to attend its annual meeting
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, April 13, 1894; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends blueprint of a map he wants printed.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 13, 1894; 8x4-3/4, 2x2-1/2; Toppan, Robert Noxon, 1836-1901
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 2p. Enc. Inquires about date of founding of the American Bank Note Company. Encloses slip with dates of business.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], April 14, 1894; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Young Men's Christian Association (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., Mimeo. L. 1p., end. Asks for last annual report.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 16, 1894; 8-1/2x5-3/4; Citizens' League Against Vice
    Cleveland, O., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Asks what books on prostitution are in A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 18, 1894; 9-1/4x6-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns package from French Ministry of Public Works, transmitted by Louis Vossion.
  - Letter to [Ella M. Morison], April 18, 1894; 8x4-3/4; Toppan, Robert Noxon, 1836-1901
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 2p. Questions about American Bank Note Co. and a Robert Scott, engraver.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 19, 1894; 9-1/4x6-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L. signed by secretary 1p., end. Enc. wanting Returns letter to be sent on to French Ministry of Public Works.
  - Notice of shipment to the American philosophical society, April 25, 1894; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Stockwell & co.
    London, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end.
  - Letter to [Ella M. Morison], April 25, 1894; 8x4-3/4; Toppan, Robert Noxon, 1836-1901
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for assistance in question of the engraver, Robert Scott.